Faster!
动作快一点
Give me a bag
拿一包给我
Big Brother
大哥
The real thing, so it's lived up is name
正货，果然是实力派
Heroine can be had in any quantity
海洛英，你要多少有多少
They say you've a way in NY.
听说你在纽约很吃得开
Let's combine.
我们一起做过江龙
To snatch your heroine business from them
将美国的海洛英市场全部抓过来
Okay, it's mutually beneficial
好，有钱大家赚
Now I want 20 kilos of that stuff
现在我要二十公斤货
Where's the money?
钱呢！
Here. Mind you.
在这里
Don't talk nonsense in front of Mr Big Brother
有一哥在这里，千万别乱说话
Trying to draw? Are you looking for hell?
敢向我拔枪，你想找死？
Great! If you work with me
有种！我跟你合作
the other families will go bust
其他家族一定没有生意可做
He's my brother.
小熊，他是我的亲兄弟
Get 20 kgs of stuff for him
拿二十公斤货来
You bustard Ping!
你这个死仔柄！
Don't move, CID!
不许动，警察
Don't move!
不许动！
Don't move! Police, drop your gun!
不许动，警察，把枪放下！
Damn it!
该死的！
Drop your gun!
把枪放下！
Big brother, run!
大哥，快跑！
Stay where you are!
别动！
Drop your gun and climb up slowly
把枪放下，慢慢起来！
No monkey bsiness! My gun has no eyes
别想着耍花样
Put your hands on your ears!
双手拉着自己的耳朵
I never flop in any mission!
老子出马，从不失手
Damn you!
你妈的！
Are you alright, Uncle Te?
你没事吧？德叔
Yes
没事
Well, an experienced fireman gets his fingers hurt?
你怎样会老猫烧须？
Nonsense!
多事！
Trying to run?
还想跑？
Stop, police
不要跑！警察
Keep away!
另叮乱来
Drop your gun! Drop or I'll kill her!
快点把枪放下！
Come on, put it down! Hear me?
快点！把枪放下，听到了没有？
Drop it or I'll shoot her dead
否则我开枪打死她，快放下！
Outrageous! You scum
岂有此理！你这个死家伙
Are you sick of living?
你这个家伙，想找死？
Get back in!
回到里面去！
Keep down
趴下！
Are you fed up with living?
你这个家伙，不想活啦？
After him!
追！
Shirley, don't come up! It's dangerous!
莎莉，不要上来，危险
- Get the frogmen to salvage - Yes, sir!
叫蛙人来打捞　　　是，长官
Did you mean to get killed?
刚才你不要命了吗？
Sorry!
对不起！
Mr Huang
黄长官
Cordon off the spot & call an ambulance
马上封锁现场，叫救伤车来
Yes, sir!
是，长官
Mr Huang...
黄长官…
Thank you all for the trouble
大家辛苦啦！
I nearly forgot to get back
差一点忘了
a bait for Shirley
那里去找回一条鱼饵给莎莉
Uncle Te, see how much our haul is
德叔，看看抓到了多少毒品
Yes, sir
是！长官
Hsiu, here you are, fixed
修哥，你的眼镜修好了再还给你
Good
好呀！
Mr Wei
韦长官
Here's a file from the USA
美国有一个档案来了
This new drug syndicate...
这一班是美国新兴的贩毒集团
is now in HK
现在来了香港
Watch their movements
你留心一下他们的动静
- Let's celebrate - Drink more
庆祝一下吧　　　喝多一杯吧
Cheers!
干杯
- Don't... - No more,please
不要…不喝了
- Really can't drink - What...
我真的不能喝　　　什么不要
- You're lying - Enough
你骗人，不能喝　　　好啦…
Well, I'll drink more tomorrow
那我明天才多喝一杯
Let's talk about it tomorrow
明天再算
Listen
事先声明
anyone making trouble tomorrow will be transferred to Shataukok
明天谁个乱来就把他调到沙头角去
Are you trying to avenge a personal grudge
这不是公报私仇吗？
What do you mean?
什么公报私仇？
Mr Huang judge for us
黄长官，你来评评道理
We celebrated for him because we took him for a friend
我们当他是朋友才替他庆祝一下
He's not taking us for friends.
他现在不当我们是朋友
What do you think?
你有什么看法
Help me, or I'll get drunk for sure
你要帮帮我，要不然我醉定了
Okay
行！
You're getting married tomorrow. Drink this
明天你结婚
Or Shirley has to clean the house for me
莎莉就要替我收拾房子
Right, Shirley will stay to clear up the rubbish
对！莎莉要一个人留下来拾垃圾
Don't think it's easy to be a housewife
你以为做家庭主妇那么容易
Do you want him to drink. I don't
那你想不想他喝，我是不太想
- Well? - Drink it
怎么样？　　　喝了它
Don't drink
不要喝
Drink this big glass
喝这么大杯
Don't side with him so soon
你还没有过门就公然护着他
We bachelors really...
看见你们俩这么恩爱
envy your true feeling
真是令我们这一班王老五羡慕了
You're lucky, you're quitting tomorrow
你就开心了，明天就离开我们不干
But we really are depressed
不过手足们就认真不开心了
Why fight?
还搏什么？
Only yesterday the doctor said my heart's weak
昨天医生才说过我的心脏不好
What?
什么？
I can't stand the shock
受不了刺激
Sometimes you can't take a doctor advice too serious
有时候医生的话用不着十足相信的
Sister, he can't stand the shock. Can you?
师姐，修哥受不了刺激，你受得嘛！
You don't drink this, you must clean the house
这一杯不喝也样要留下来收拾房子
Go and collect the ashes
你去执骨好了
Drinking's bad for health. What about venting our feelings?
斗酒伤身不好的，不如斗气好吗？
That suits me better. I'm a virgin
更对胃口，我是处男
I've lots of grievances, lets vent them
横竖谷了一肚子气，来，斗吧！
Ah Yu, come here!
阿有，过来！
What's it, Hsiu?
什么事，修哥？
What's wrong with you?
你是怎么搅的？
Fix him for me
替我摆平他
Is that an order or a friendly request?
修哥，这个是命令还是私人感情？
Only a friend would tell you to do this
是自己人才叫你这么做
Yes, sir
是，长官
No peeping and no moving of lower jaws
这个游戏规则不准看，下颚不准动
Anyone blowing the egg to an opponent win
鸡蛋吹到对方那一边就算赢
Ready!
准备！
Start!
开始！
Hsiu, I'm on your side. Why tease me?
修哥，我帮你，你还耍我？
Either we play today or never
今天不玩就再没有机会玩了
Even if you...
玩呀？
were my master, I'd tease you.
就算你是我师父我也要耍你一次
Amy...
爱美…
Terrific!
好厉害
Make fun of mel?
整我！?
Stop that. Amy really is coming
不要玩了，爱美真的来了
I don't care about her
才不要理
- So what? - It's you who don't care about me
来了又怎么样？
Everything alright?
没什么
Amy
爱美
What?
什么？
How dare you lay hands on my girl?
连我的女朋友你也敢耍
- Protect me, Madam - Don't go
师姐保护我　　　你别走
Forget it!
算了吧！
Outrageous!
岂有此理！
Bastard, how dare you?
你这个死家伙，来真的
Anyone teasing Amy will get it
谁敢耍爱美？我就要他好看
He's flaring up
玩出火了…
What's the matter with you?
你怎么啦？
It's alright
没事
They're always so wild.
他们都是这么疯的，别理他们
Never mind them
烧东西吃
- Mr Huang, stop him - Your guys...
黄长官，挡着他　　　你两个家伙…
What're you up to again?
又玩什么新花样？
That bastard hit me
这个臭小子打我
Don't go so wild, will you?
好心你们别玩得这样疯
Mr Huang, now is the Happy Hour
报告黄长官，现在欢乐时光
We'll go on even if Madam ordered us to stop
就算是干妈下命令
Dare you even to tease me?
你两个马驷连我也敢耍
Sorry, sir. We'll go down to accompany you
对不起！长官，我们下水陪你
Good, you dared to fling me down
来得好，敢把我扔下来
Come in!
进来吧！
It really got into my head
喝得我全身发烫
Get me a cup of coffee, will you?
给我弄杯咖啡解解酒好不好
Thank you
谢谢你！
For me?
送给我的吗？
I planned to give it to Shirley
本来我是想拿来送给莎莉的
Now I think it suits you better
不过现在想起来还是你合用一点
It depends
那就要看看先
How could it suit me?
这东西怎么会合我用？
Not for tonight
今天晚上你就不合用
As of tomorrow
不过从明天开始
you're to work like a slave
就要疼爱莎莉，做她的佣人
You tease me last time
上一次整我
Well have some tear-gas
好，让我给你享用一点催泪气体
So you'll cry on your wedding day
好让你结婚也哭个饱
Don't exaggerate
你不是这么夸张吧？
Okay, you win
我真是服了你
Make way
让开！
Let me
让我来
No, you're clumsy
不用，笨手笨脚
So mush the better
那就最好了
Let me taste this nice cup of coffee
好！先享受一杯咖啡
Your heart's weak. Don't drink coffee anymore
你心脏不好，以后不准喝咖啡
I only meant to fool them
怎么你当真的？我是骗他们的
You've fooled me too
那你连我也骗？
No
不是
Stop lying, tell me the truth
不准骗我，快点老老实实说
Do you love Shirley?
你是不是喜欢莎莉？
If you don't say it, it means you don't
不肯说就是不喜欢了
No, but...
不是，不过…
I still can't make up my mind after such a long time
不过想了这么久就是还没有决定
I love her then
那我喜欢好了
You're not sincere
说得这么随便，就是没有诚意
- They're pushing - Go now
讲完了没有？　　　催你了，走吧
I'll go then
那我走了
- Bye-bye
拜拜！　　　拜拜！
Really heartless, idiot
真没心肝，笨蛋…！
Take it off first
先脱了它
Right
是啊！
Remember to collect the bride at 10 tomorrow
记着明天早上十点我来接新娘
Wear a necktie
结一条领带
Thank you. Bye-bye
谢谢！拜拜！
Try it at once
快点来试一试
Really beautiful
真漂亮
The flower on the head is beautiful
头花很好看
Hsiu
修哥
Don't run
不要跑
Call an ambulance at once!
快点叫救伤车！
Hsiu
修哥
Shir...Shirley, I...
莎…莎莉，我…
Hsiu...
修哥…
What happened...
什么事
C.I.D.
警察
Heavenly Father of all men
全人类的天父啊！
We pray especially for those we love
我们特为所爱
but can't see any more
而以后不能再见的人向主祷告
May you bless them
求主赐平安予他们
& shine on them
以永恒之光照临他们
May thy love, wisdom & omnipotence
在主的慈爱，智慧及全能权柄当中
Be demonstrated...
愿天父的完全旨意
in them
所有的良善目的能在他们身上献上
We pray in jesus' name, Amen
此乃我主耶稣基督要求，阿门！
Why are you back from your leave?
你正在休假，你干嘛还回来？
There's no point in taking leave now
现在休假也没意义
Michael, I'm applying for return to duty
米高，我想申请销假
Good. Work may do you good
也好，有事情做对你会好一点
Master. I'm in trouble. You must help
八爷
You made things so bad.
你这个家伙，搅到这么严重
Who'd help you?
手足们怎么肯帮你
Here's a potion of American ginseng.
这样吧，这里有一服花旗华
See if it will help
看它能不能够帮到你
Don't move. Police
不要动，警察
Yu, handcuff him
阿有，把他铐上
Don't move!
不要动
Where's Swatow Hsiung?
潮洲雄在什么地方？
I don't know. Miss
不知道，大姐
I don't know...
不知道…
You're his best friend! Speak up!
你跟他是好兄弟，怎么会不知道？
Are you going to speak or not?
不肯讲…不肯讲…
Maybe these 2 monsters...
长官，他不肯讲
may speak
说不定这两个怪兽会讲
- Sorry, I don't know anything - Let's go
不要，我什么都不知道　　　走
Don't, Mr Big
不要，老大
Go over there!
到那边去！
Don't scare madam
不要吓倒我的女上司
Be smart and speak
你们两个聪明的就快点讲
I really don't know
我真的不知道
Don't blame me...
如果不肯讲的话
if your bottom gets burnt
烫焦了屁股我不负责
Hear that?
听到了没有？
I really don't know
我真的不知道
Well, are you going to speak or not
怎么啦？不讲是吗？
Speak up!
讲！
Take off has pants!
脱裤子
You're not speaking? Scald him
不讲是吗？烫他
Good
好啊
I enjoy doing it.
我最喜欢烫屁股，岂有此理
You don't care a damn about me
敢不把老子放在眼内
Speak up!
还不快讲？讲不讲？
No?
还不讲
He's collapsed
昏过去了
His bottom's got burnt
当然啦！屁股给烫焦了
That one outside may last longer
外面那一个可能熬得住一点
Okay, scald him
好！烫他
Take off your pants
脱裤子！
I'll speak... I only know he's sailing tomorrow
我讲・一我只知道他明天坐船逃亡
But I don't know...
在什么地方我就不知道
where
我就知这么多
Keep away...
不要过来
Look, we've got so many complaint
看看我们收到多少投诉
You took action without my approval
未经批准，就擅自行动
Used violence to hurt suspects.
滥用暴力，伤害疑犯
How can I protect you
叫我怎么保住你？
Inspector Ho Shih-ling, you've let me down
何雪玲督察
Sorry, sir
对不起！长官
What good to say sorry now?
现在说对不起…有什么用？
How long have you been in the police force?
你当了警察这么久
With your relationship with Hsiu
以你跟阿修的关系
you shouldn't handle this case
根本就不应该办这件案子
We're legally...
我跟阿修还没有正式结婚
still unmarried
法律上不算是夫妻
Shut up!
住口
To talk about law
讲法律？我们当警察
we'll all die martyrs
随时随地都可能殉职
Vengeance makes us...
如果每一个人都要报仇
no different from rascal
跟流氓有什么分别？
You're unfit to be a policeman
你没有资格当警察
Sorry, sir, Insp Ho's operation...
对不起！长官，何雪玲督察…
got my verbal approval
这一次行动是经过我口头批准
I know the whole thing well
整件事情我最清楚
Don't cover her up
你不用维护她
I only feel that I've a responsibility
我只是觉得我需要负责
Good fix it then
好！你这么喜欢负责，你搅定它
If anything goes wrong again, mind your future
再有什么差池，小心你自己的前途
Yes, sir
是！长官
I don't mind bearing the blame for you
我替你背这个黑锅也没所谓
But remember foolhardiness doesn't always work
可是有时候办案不是靠冲动就行
- Mr Wang! - Uncle Te, how's it?
黄长官！　　　德叔，怎么样？
We've a glue
有线索
Swatow Hsiung will leave HK
潮洲雄会在两点钟到三门仔码头
at Sam Mun Pier at two
坐船离开香港
Buddy, when will the ship sail?
老兄，还有多久才开船？
After these drums have been moved
搬完这几桶就行了
Swatow Hsiung
潮洲雄
Don't move! Sail quickly!
不许动，快开船
Sail, or I'll shoot you dead
开船，否则一枪打死你
Release the rope
解缆
Brother, don't shoot, it's loaded with gasoline
老大，你不要开枪，全船都是汽油
My whole family's on it.
我一家大小全在船上，求求你
Don't shoot. I beg you.
你千万不要开枪
Release the rope, faster!
解缆，快一点
Go to hell!
去死吧！
Don't move!
不要动
You're violating the law
你这么做会犯法
Tai-li, tell the bastard to bring the boat back to shore
泰利，叫船家搬船驶回岸去
Yu, keep the evidence on the spot and bring it back
阿有
Yes, Mr Wong
知道了，黄长官
Captain, show me your licence and I.D.
船主，把牌照和身份证拿出来
Not my fault, sir
长官，不关我的事
Back to the shore.
没事了，先驶回岸去
We'll take your statement then
上了岸再替你录口供
I wanted to kill him too
我也很想杀他
No more
别再说了
We're police
但是我们是警察
What are you doing?
干什么？
Old Te. I know the American ginseng case
老鬼德，花旗华那一件事我知道
Give me a chance. It's for everyone's good
放我一条生路，大家都好
Save your nonsense for the Tomb Festival
你的废话真多，拜山时再说
Mr Hueng...
黄长官
Fix all these
把这些全部搅定
Mr Heung, do you know the American ginseng case?
黄长官，你知不知道花旗华的事？
Mr Heung
黄长官
Be smart & let me go
聪明的你就放我一马
or we'll both perish
否则大家同归于尽
Kill me! See how you'll...
开枪打死我好了
make your report
开枪吧
Get away...
你走呀…
- A snatcher... - Don't move
抢枪呀…不要动
Go and see him
过去看看他
Over here, you stay to watch him
过来这边，你留在这里看着他
Yes, Madam
是，长官
Come here! Come here to mark the seat
你过来，过来这边划位
Stop the others from coming
不要让其他人走过来
Old Te, you need this gun...
老鬼德，你是不是给吓坏了
for evidence
这柄枪要拿回来做证
Oh. I forgot
是…忘记了
He was stunned
吓呆了
This coffee came from my friend in Brazil
这些咖啡是个巴西朋友送给我
Try it
来试一下
Thank you, sir
谢谢长官
I've read the report on yesterday's incidence
我看过昨天那一件事的报告
Mr Wei
韦长官
We got no full marks
这一件案虽然拿不到满分
but I'm satisfied with the result
但是我已经很满意
Had we captured on alive
可惜留不到活口
we could get more clues
不然可以问多一点线索
I like you...
我就是喜欢你这一点
for your serious attitude
对自己要求这么严格
You're already so busy. Take 2 days' leave
你已经够忙了，放两天假休息一下
Thank you, sir
谢谢长官
A fish has swallowed the bait.
有鱼上钓了，我钓到他了
Go & see
你过来看看
A big fish
好大条呀
Even you've caught it, must be a stupid fish
你也会钓到鱼
So you're stupider!
不知道是你笨还是他笨？
Get it back right away
快点把他抓回来
Over there! Catch it, get it back
在那边，捉着他，抓他回来
Take care
小心点
I've seen it. So it's a crafty fish
看错了，原来鱼也是这么古惑
Is it?
是吗
There's no lack of stupid fish.
不要紧，里面都是笨鱼
Let's catch
再钓别一条好了
I daren't convey anything to you
我不敢希望你表示些什么？
Let's me teach you yatching.
我教你驾帆船
Some day we'll cross the Pacific
以后跟你一起横渡太平洋
Come!
来！
No...
不行…
Turn...
转…
Which way
转那一个方向？
This way?
转这一边吗？
Right. Turn
对了，转…
I did it
我行了
Uncle Te
德叔
Spend more time on Amy...
阿有，有空要多点陪伴艾美
to strengthen the ties
不然很容易分手
I wish I could
我也想…
But I'm a policeman
谁叫我当警察？
Excuse me
我先走了
Okay! Bye-bye
好！拜拜！
This is Yu
我是阿有
What happened?
什么事？
Mr. Hueng. I've caught Uncle Te...
黄长官，我亲眼看到德叔…
dealing drug with foreigner
跟几个洋鬼子买卖毒物
Impossible
没有可能
It's true. I've the video tape for evidence
是真的，我拍了录影带做证
Let's make immediate action. What do you suggest?
我不如马上采取行动？
No, it could be complicated
不要，这一件事可能牵涉很大
Bring all the tapes to the station for me to see
你明天把录影带…
Anything important?
有急事？
Nothing serious. I'll take you home
小事情，我先送你回去
Let's go
走吧
Cindy wants me to remind you...
仙蒂姐叫我提醒你
today is Amy birthday
今天是艾美的生日
I know. I know.
我知道了，我当然知道了
See the cake & flowers is ready.
蛋糕和花都帮你买了
Go & be pardon.
快点去逗他原谅你
What are you waiting for! Get in!
还想什么？快上车！
Girls have to be soothed
女人嘛！你不求不拜很容易
Go now. Amy will be off duty soon
快点去！艾美快要下班了，走吧
You're meddlesome
你真多事
Only 1 5 minutes for fooling around
泡妞只许十五分钟
Thank you
谢谢
Amy
艾美
Can I help you, sir?
先生，买机票吗？
Yes.
是呀！
I want 2 tickets for a trip with my girlfriend
我想买两张机票
It's her birthday. Happy birthday!
因为是她的生日，祝你生日快乐！
It's yours.
送给你的
What's it on the tape? Let me show it
拍了些什么？让我先看看
What are you going to cook for me?
回去煮些什么给我吃？
Let's eat cakes after dinner
吃完了饭吃蛋糕
Don't touch my videotape recorder! Open the door
你干嘛看我的录影机？开门！
- Open up! - What are you doing?
开门呀！　　　干什么？
It's none of your business
不关你的事
Come out...
出来…
Who told you to watch my videotape
谁叫你看我的录影带？
Well, you're keeping such a serious thing from me
好呀！连这么严重的事也不告诉我？
What is it?
什么事
Are you taking me for your brother
你有没有把我当做兄弟？
Speak up...
你说…
Uncle Te's your master
你真笨！德叔是你师父
but he's keeping it from you
他有没有告诉你他贩买海洛英
It means he doesn't trust me
哪就是不相信我，是不是
Who knows? You're taking him for your dad
很难说，你把德叔看成是你老爸
How do I know you're an accessory?
我怎么知道你有没有份
Would I be an accessory to this?
这一种勾当，会说我有份
I went through everything with you
我跟你一起出生入死这么久
and you suspect me?
你这样怀疑我？
You're so impulsive. How could I tell you?
你呀！你这么冲动，我怎么告诉你？
It would only ruin you
告诉你岂不是害了你？
What have you to fear now?
你现在怕什么，怕什么？
I'm not afraid either. Be he a tiger
我也不怕，你怕什么？管他是老虎
Or my own dad.
就是我的亲生爸爸
I'll take him...
他贩买海洛英我一样要抓他
if he sells drug
你知不知？
I'll go & arrest him right now
我马上就去抓他
Let's go!
放手
Don't be so impulsive!
你别这么冲动好不好！
Any rash action will ruin everything
你再这么冲动就什么都被你破坏了
Aren't we brothers?
我们是不是兄弟？
Listen
我现在告诉你
this is only between me & Mr Huang
这一件事情只有我跟黄长官知道
And me
还有我
Yes...!
对啦…！
Remember, don't take individual action...
记着，有什么发现
if you discover anything. Okay?
不要私自行动，OKAY？
Bad. I must explain to Amy
糟了，我要找艾美解释
Don't do anything foolish!
别乱来！
Listen
你听我说
It hurts!
好痛呀！
Go now, or I'll call the police
你再不走我就报警
and accuse you of trespassing
说有一个警察擅闯民居
You must be joking
你不是这样开玩笑吧？
Who's joking with you?
谁跟你开玩笑，跟你的朋友玩好了
Amy
艾美
I won't see you anymore. Go away!
不想看到你，走呀！
My hand!
我的手呀！
You're not going? I will
你赖死不走是吗？我走
What are you doing?
干什么？
Don't go
不许动
Are you taking me for a criminal?
你当我是犯人？
Yes. I sue you for willful damage
是！我控告你…
to a policeman's pride
蓄意伤害警务人员自尊心
I must question you now
我现在盘问你
I've followed you all the way
我追了你十多条街
and kept saying 'sorry'
说了几十句对不起
What else do you want?
你还想我怎么样？
Mr Fang. I want you to have some respect for me.
方长官，我想你尊重一下我
You come to see me when you're in the mood
你心情好的时候就来找我
You leave me behind
你心情不好的时候就扔下我
& say sorry when you're not
说声对不起就算数
What are you taking me for?
你把我看成是什么人？
My girlfriend
当你是我的女朋友
worthy of my respect
值得我对你说对不起
Have my action to show how important you're to me
值得我用行动来表示对我多重要
I'll keep you company till tomorrow morning
我现在开始陪你到明天早上
I'll quit as a policeman. Okay?
警察也不做，够了没有？
No
不够
I'll give you...
市民也不做，街也不去
as a citizen to go out
连传呼机也不要
I'll break with anyone else, but I won't let you go
跟所有人绝不放你，我绝不放你
Let me go!
你快点放了我
No, you mean everything to me
不放，今天晚上还是重色轻友
I can't cook if you don't let me go, jerk
你不放手我怎么煮饭？死相
Right, right, I must let you go
是啊，你说得对，让我放了你
Let me see if you're hurt
等我先看看你有没有受伤
A policeman gets more sentence for indecent assault
警察非礼，罪加一等
I couldn't care less
彻职也值得
Chun-yu, what are you up to? Come & help
俊友，你搅什么鬼？进来帮帮我
I'm preparing a birthday gift for you
我在给你弄一份生日礼物
Come and eat
来吃东西
The big gift is here
大礼物来了
Am I sweet?
我可不可爱
Take me
整个人送给你
Disgusting...
真核突…
Shirley, have you got the key?
莎莉，有没有钥匙？
Yes
以前就没有
but Hsiu never allowed me to open it
这一个柜阿修一直都不让我打开
And I don't know what it contains
我也不知道有什么放在里面
Did you give him this?
你送给他的？
He always kept everything to himself
他什么事都放在心里
Over $10 million! Impossible for a man
一千多万，以他的家当和收入
of his family background!
没有可能有这么多钱
And these 2 passports! What are they for?
还有两个护照，要来什么用？
This must be ill-gotten money
这些钱是用不正当手段赚回来的
These passports are to help use another identity
这两个护照
To get out of HK, in case of need
随时可以用另一个身份离开香港
Wish my reasoning was wrong
希望我的想法是错的
I've recently got a tip-off that
最近我接到线报
Someone abused...
说我们的部门…
his power for dope-push
有人利用职权贩卖海洛英
I thought...
我一直以为他很忠直
he was honest
原来什么都是假的
Shriley, I know how you feel
莎莉，我很明白你的心情
Please face up to reality
希望你可以面对现实
There's indeed something wrong with him
阿修的确有可疑，不过你放心
But I'll help you find out the truth
我一定帮你，一定帮你查出真相
Buy a flag, sir...
先生，买支旗…
Follow that white car in front
跟着前面的白色车
Royal HK policeman, no more police affair
皇家警察，你不想着警察局的事吗？
No
我才不理它死活
I'm all yours tonight
今天晚上我整个人都属于你
GET LOST
GET LOST
Police
警察
Drop your gun!
把枪放下！
Drop your gun too, old Te
老鬼德，把你的枪也扔掉
Terry, I...
泰利，我
Stay to speak to the judge. Fling it to see
留下来跟法官说，把枪扔到海里去
Get your handcuffs & put them on
拿你的手铐把两个洋鬼子铐上
Those two foreigners
把他们铐上！
Terry
泰利
You're trafficking in drugs
你贩毒？
As a policeman, you know the law and violate it
你身为警察人员，竟然知法犯法
I was as hot-tempered when I was young
我年轻的时候
I understood
我明白
Why did you do that?
我不明白你为什么要这样做？
I've followed you since I left school
我从学堂出来就一直跟着你
I took you for my master, my dad
我当你是师父，当你是我的爸爸
But now it's all over between us
但是今天我跟你的关系到此为止
You're under arrest
我要拉你
Arrest me? I was braver than you
拉我？当年我比你还勇
What did I get for arresting some small frys
为了拉几个小卒
2 lousy medals
两个破奖章
When the weather's bad
一翻风落雨就痛得我…
it hurts & I can't sleep
一整个晚上都睡不着
They did it again once the got discharged
他们坐完牢出来，不也是一样贩毒
I am a small fry too
我也是个小卒
A small fry of a big shot
我不理是小卒还是大魔头
I don't care
总之撞在我手里一样没情讲
Terry, you're still young & you've your idea
泰利，你还年轻，你有理想是对的
When you reach...
但是当你好像我家里的环境
my age & are
这么需要钱
In my straitened circumstances.
我什么也不懂，什么也没有
You'll see how important money is
你就会知道钱是那么重要
Shut up! Don't find an excuse for yourself
你住口！你不用找籍口原谅自己
Terry, let me go
泰利，放阿叔一马
Sorry, Uncle Te
我不可以放你，德叔
I know you're nice to me, but I've no choice
我知道你对我好，我也不想
I caught Te dealing in drugs with...
黄长官，我在赤柱圣士提反湾…
2 foreigners in Stephen Bay, Stanley
捉到德叔跟两个洋鬼子交易
Come on
来啊…！
Stop...!
停手…！
Hey guy, move and you are death
不要动，除非你想死
Sir
黄长官
these 2 foreigners dealt in drugs with Uncle Te
就是这两个洋鬼子跟德叔交易毒品
I've got the tape for evidence
我已经拍了录影带做证据
Well done! You've done a great credit
好！你做得很好，立了大功
Handcuff Uncle Te
把德叔铐起来！
Yes, sir
是！长官
I'll fix everything with your boss. Leave now
你们走吧！我跟你的波士解决一切
Okay!
好的！
Why do you want to kill him?
你干嘛要杀死他？
You'll die for sure if he doesn't
他不死你就死定了
I'd rather go to jail than to kill him
我宁愿坐牢，也不愿杀死他
You're my best aide.
你是我至好的手下
I'll cover you up
我一定会罩着你的
I quit
我不干了
Finish this case for me first
替我办完了这一件案再说
You know how to handle...
这里的事你知道怎么处理
the things here
就这么决定
You gave me personal assurance that
你曾经向我亲口保证过
Everything would be okay
说这一次的合作一定不会出事
Only about the stuff.
我保证的是那些货
I'm not your nanny
没有说个当你的褓母
I've overassessed you.
我真是高估了你的实力
You can't even finish a kid
连一个小子也搅不定
Now the co-operation is over between us
我跟你的合作到此为至
Our market in New York is so big
我们纽约的市场那么大
Many in HK would vie to be my sidekick
香港这边有很多人争着做我的拍挡
Okay, no problem
OKAY！没问题
Listen
不过我告诉你
no one dare touch any deals I touched
凡是我碰过的生意没有人敢再碰
Hong Kong is mine, and you're not the only market in USA
香港是我的，美国市场不单止你们
Get out of HK & return to New York
马上离开香港回纽约去
Hold it, Michael!
J慢着！米高
I came here to make money, not to make enemy
我来这里是赚钱，不是找仇人
Okay, I'll trust you one more time
好！我再相信你一次
Well, if you want co-operation, do one thing for me
好！如果要合作就帮我做一点事
I want 200 kilos of stuff tomorrow night
明天晚上我要二百斤货
This is my A No.
这一个是我的户口号码
Credit the money into it You'll get the stuff tomorrow night
明天早上你存了钱
The killer can never get away
这个凶手一定跑不掉
We can get hold of him for sure
手足们一定可以抓到他
Morning!
早！
What's wrong? Why are you all wearing a stone face?
干嘛？你们每一个人都苦口苦脸
A bereavement?
死了老爸是不是？
- Ah Yu - Ah Yu, come in!
阿有　　　阿有，进来！
Shirley, please go out for a while
莎莉，请你先出去一会
Ah Yu, close the door please
阿有，关门，谢谢！
I've ascertained Hsiu's drug-trafficking
我查到阿修贩毒
Is that so? Does Shirley know it?
真的？莎莉知不知道？
I'm not too sure
我不敢肯定
Would she be an accessory?
会不会她也有份？
We must take more care from now on
我想我们以后都要小心点
I don't think Shirley has a hand on it
我真不相信莎莉都有份
Here's a cassette of Te's drug-trafficking
这一盒是德叔跟毒贩交易的录影带
It's of serious consequence
我想这一件事，事关重大
Formerly it was Hsiu, now It's Uncle Te
之前有阿修，现在是德叔
How many more are involved
究竟还有多少人牵涉在里面？
I don't know
我也不知道
Yu, have you got any other evidence?
阿有，你还有没有其他证据
I've put a tape at Amy's
我过了一盒带子放在艾美家里
Is that so?
是吗？
Don't worry.
不用怕，艾美也不知道…
Amy knows nothing about it
我放了一盒带子在她家里
We must get it back as soon as possible
我们要尽快把那盒带子拿回来
For Amy's safety
为了艾美的安全
don't tell anyone about it
你不要再对任何人说
I know what to do
我知道该怎么做了
Shirley, please come in
莎莉，请你进来
Yu, I want to talk to you
阿有，有一件事要跟你说
Keep cool.
你不要冲动，你要冷静一点
Something happened last night
昨天晚上发生了一件事
What is it?
什么事？
Come in
进来
Mr Huang
黄长官
Shirley
莎莉，这是重要证物
put this important item in a safe
替我放在保险箱里
Aren't you afraid she might be Te's accompany
你不怕她是德叔的同党
Impossible
不会吧！
Terry was killed yesterday
昨天泰利被人杀死了
What?
什么？
He knew about Old Te
他知道老鬼德的事，这就…
I must go out for a while
我出去一会
Old Te, hold it! You creep!
不要走，老鬼德，你这个死家伙
You ruined Terry. I'll kill you!
你害死了泰利，我打死你
Ah Yu
阿有
Are you crazy? Uncle Te's taking Terry for his own son.
你疯啦！德叔当泰利是自己的孩子
You're mistaken
你误会了
Yu, don't get the wrong idea.
阿有，你别胡思乱想
He won't do that
他怎么会这么做？
What happened?
发生什么事？
A policeman trafficking in drugs can do anything
他当警察也贩毒，有什么事干不出？
Quiet! We're all friends. Let's talk it over
别吵！大家自己兄弟，有话好说
Let me go!
放开我
I've proof of your drug-trafficking
我有证据证明你贩毒
I've already reported to Mr Huang. I'll testify against you
我已经报告黄长官，我一定指证你
Yu, don't be impulsive
阿有，不要这么冲动
You did report to me
你是曾经向我报告
but I can't accuse Te
但在我没有看到证据之前
Before I see the evidence
不可以一口说定是德叔
I must be him
不用看了，一定是他
I've got tapes of your drug-trafficking
我有你跟贩毒交易的录影带
Nonsense
你胡说
Shirley, run it for him
莎莉，放给他看
Run it
放吧！
How come?
怎么没有？
Obviously the cassette has been swapped
原来是有的，我的录影带被人换了
What? Where's the evidence?
换什么，证据呢？
You yourself are under suspicion
作贼心虚，我说你才有嫌疑
You're exposing your own crime
你自己作贼心虚
Last time Hsiu got killed
上一次修哥之死
because you planted a smoke bomb
是因为你在他的车上装上烟幕弹
This time Terry got killed because you abandoned your duty
这一次泰利的死是因为你擅离职守
What explanation can you give?
你有什么解释？
I have other evidence
我还有证据
I saw him putting heroin in...
我亲眼看见他把海洛英放在里面
I also saw you put heroin into the locker
我也看见你把海洛英放在贮物柜里
Let's search together
要搜就大家一起搜
I'm not afraid. You're finished. Give me the key
我怕你吗？你死定了，把钥匙拿来
Don't try anything foolish
别乱来！
Keep away!
走开！
Uncle Te, the key!
德叔，把锁匙拿出来
Pheasant
山鸡
Sorry, Uncle Te
不好意思，德叔
Keep cool
冷静，不要乱来
Uncle Te, you really did it
德叔，真的是你
You put aside my book & said it was missing
你收起了我的书说不见了
Will you search more thoroughly?
你搜清楚一点行不行？
We've searched everything. There's nothing
全部搜过了，什么都没有
- Let's search his home - Ah Yu,
搜他的家，一定有的　　　阿有
- your locker - Open it and see
那你的贮物柜…　　　打开来看看
Okay
好呀！
Search!
搜吧！
- You really did it - No
真是你的　　　不是我的
Yu, calm down
阿有，冷静一点
Are you going to tell me this is flour?
你不是想告诉我这一包是面粉吧？
This bag is not mine
这包东西不是我的
It was frame-up
你插赃嫁祸？
Believe up me, Shirley, believe me
你相信我，莎莉，相信我
Now I won't trust anyone
现在我什么人也不会再相信
I only believe in truth and evidence
只会相信事实，相信证据
You're arrested for drug possession
我现在用藏毒的罪名拘捕你
Shirley, I know Te is not alone in the
莎莉
Frame-up. Soon I'll seek them out!
那一班人我早晚会找出来
Watch out
你小心一点
Do you mean us?
你这不是说我们吗？
- Don't frame us - Don't get us involved
你冤枉好人你自己不好就算了
- Because you're evil - Quiet
别把大家都拖到水里去　　　别吵
This is not a market
这里是街市？
You're the Discipline Unit
你们是纪律部队
I'll investigate the accusation between Yu & Uncle Te
阿有跟德叔互相指控，我会撒查
You'll also be subject to internal investigation
你们也是一样，要接受内部词查
I'm drug investigation Special Operation
我是毒品调查科特别行动组督察
Insp Ho
何雪玲
You're suspected of drug possession. What's your name?
我怀疑你藏毒，叫什么名字？
Fang Shun-yu
方信有
Profession
职业
A member of the Royal Hong Kong Police Force
香港皇家警察队雇员
With the Drug Investigation Dept of the Special Operations
逮属毒品调查科特别行动组
Where do you live?
住在那里？
You know it already
明知故问
As a policeman, you should know...
你曾经是警察，你应该知道…
I know better in this respect
这一点我比你更清楚
I've discovered heroin in your locker
我在你的贮物柜找到海洛英
how do you explain that?
你怎么解释
I was framed. Why should I explain?
怎么解释？我是被人插赃嫁祸的
Possess no drugs, why should I be question
我没有藏毒，我不用接受你的盘问
There's no evidence to support your state
没有一样证据支持…
You mean you've proof against me?
那就是你有证据可以指证我了
Can you think of anything to prove your innocence?
你想清楚
Law requires evidence
法律是要讲证据的
All your statement may be used as evidence in court
你所说的一切都会作为是呈堂证供
Okay, I'll give my statement
好，我说
I deal in drugs, smuggling and
我藏毒，贩毒，走私
Resort to killing, arson and robbery
杀人放火，打劫
Take it down as a matter of routine! Come on
你写好了，例行手续嘛！你写吧！
Evidence in Court? Take it down!
呈堂证供是吗？写吧！
Ah Yu
阿有
My name is Shih Shun-yu, I don't know you
我的名字叫方信有，我不认识你
I suspect Insp Ho Hsueh-ling's conspiracy against me
我怀疑督察何雪玲串谋害我，写吧！
Take it down! Sue me
写呀，告我好了
The time is 20th Oct 1988 at 3 p.m.
现在是八八年一月二十日下午三点
I'm Anti-Narcotics Bureau detective
我是扫毒组探员方信有
Fang Shun-yu No.3368
探员编号3368
I suspect my Sergeant Feng Chien-te of drug-trafficking
我怀疑同组警长冯建德贩毒
As a result of 3 days probe & trace
经过三天的调查和跟踪
I've discovered him
现在发现他在渡海轮上面
dealing in drugs with...
跟两个身份未明的…
2 unidentified foreigners on a ferry
外籍人仕进行毒品交易
deduced that he used his detective identity
据我暂时的推测
to cover up
他是利用扫毒组探员身份掩饰
his trafficking activities
进行毒品交易
Mr Huang
黄长官？
Mr Huang?
黄长官！？
I'm Old Te, I've searched the whole house
老鬼德，我把全个房子都搜过了
There are many cassettes
录影带有很多盒
but not the one you mention
不过没有看到你所说的那一盒
I'm back first
我先回来
Any clues?
有没有线索？
Go back & retire. I'll take charge here
你先回去休息，这里由我来处理
Mr Huang
黄长官
Ah Yu, I believe you are innocent
阿有，我相信你是无辜的
Mr Huang, you must help me on this
黄长官，这一次你一定要帮我
Who else knows
老鬼德这一件事除了我知道之外
the old Te case besides me?
还有什么人知道？
Terry
泰利
You know Terry is impulsive
你明知泰利这个人这么冲动
Now you've ruined him & yourself
你不单只害死了他
The first thing is to prove your innocence
现在首先要做的就是替你洗脱嫌疑
Take me to get the copy
你不是说有一盒录影带拷贝吗？
of cassette you mentioned
带我去拿
Don't you trust me?
你不相信我？
Shun-yu
信有
Have you seen the cassette I taped yesterday?
我昨天录的那盒带子你有没有看到
Yes
有
Besides Te, there's...
除了德叔之外还有…
Go on! Speak up!
还有什么？你快说！
I don't know, I don't know anything
我不知道，我什么都不知道
Do you know or not?
究竟知不知道？
I know nothing
我什么都不知道
That cassette is very important to Yu
那一盒带子对有仔很重要
Bring it if you know where it is
知道在什么地方就马上拿出来
There's no such a cassette
你不用找了，没有呀！
There must be.
一定有的
I ran it on this VTR recorder last night
我昨天晚上在这一部机过带子的
Have you ever taken it away?
你想想有没有拿过出来
No, I didn't even touch it
没有，我碰也没有碰过
Just now you said you got it
你刚才又说有？
Without it
没有那一盒带子
I can't clear myself. I'll be in jail
我是水洗不清要坐一辈子牢
Do you know it or don't you?
究竟你知不知道
I know...
我知道了
Take out now
知道还不拿出来
You don't want Yu to get into trouble
你也不想有仔有事
I promise
我答应你
I'll quit once I'm cleared
我洗脱嫌疑之后就不当警察
I'm so scared!
我好怕呀！
Why?
你怕什么？
It's okay if you find the cassette
找到这一盒带子我就没事了
Well, Yu, we must leave
阿有，好了，我们该走了
Amy's going to be alright, I'll have someone watch her
艾美不会有事，我会派人看着她
I'm Michael
我是米高
now at 5 Conduit Garden 26th floor
我现在在干德道
Send someone, a woman needs protection
有一个女人需要保护，马上派人来
Yu, we're in a hurry
阿有，我们要赶时间
Excuse me
我先走了
Shun Yu, I want no protection
信有，我不要人保护
I'm alright, I'll return soon
没事的，你放心，我很快就回来
Bye-bye!
拜拜
Let's go!
走吧！
Please call Amy, 3368 urgent.
请传呼3 3 68，艾美，有急事
Tell her to call my home
叫她马上打电话来
Mr Huang, let's return to Hq
黄长官，现在回去警察局
Handcuff me
先把我铐上
Okay, this will save us from unnecessary complaints
也好
Bear with it now & soon you'll clear your's
多熬一阵子
Mr Huang, sorry for the trouble
黄长官，给你添麻烦了
Don't mention it
应该的
Mr Huang
黄长官
it was these foreigners who deal with Te
就是这两个洋鬼子跟德叔交易
Turn around and arrest them!
快一点掉头，去抓他！
Amy, what happened?
艾美，什么事？
Shirley, Michael masterminded...
莎莉，米高是奸的
Te's dope-pushing
是他幕后主使德叔贩毒
He won't do that
米高不会这样吧？
It's true. He just took that cassette away
是真的
I'm scared
我现在好怕
Keep calm, don't go away.
你镇定一点，千万别走开
Tell me in detail
我立刻来，到时候你详细告诉我
Michael masterminded Te's dope-pushing
米高是奸的，是他主使德叔贩毒
Believe me...
你相信我…
Freeze
站住
Come in!
进来！
Why are you coming to see me at this hour
这么晚来找我，有什么事？
You're depressed, don't drink so much
心情不好，别喝那么多酒
After so much has happened
近来发生了这么多事
go for a pleasure tour
不如去旅行散散心
Amy spoke to me over the phone before her dead
艾美在临死之前跟我通过电话
Is that so?
是吗？
What did she say to you?
她跟你说过什么话
Yu is innocent of drug possession
阿有被控藏毒是无辜的
A big shot is behind
贩毒的那一个是德叔
Te's drug-trafficking
幕后有一个大人物
Who?
哪是谁？
You should know better
你应该比我更清楚
You suspect me.
你是怀疑我了
Call the police to arrest
为什么不马上报警拉我？
I would have done it
如果是第二个我会这样做
But we're good friends
不过我们是好朋友
But now you've a chance to give yourself up
我不马上报警就是给你自首的机会
Can you testify against me like this?
凭你一句话就可以指证我吗？
Yes, with my name & position in the police force
以我今天在警队的声誉
My words will convince everyone
我讲的话一定有人相信
Now listen, I Michael Wong am a drug-trafficking
现在我告诉你，我米高黄贩毒
What have got anything to accuse me of it
你凭什么指控我？
I've a copy of Te's drug-trafficking tape
我有德叔贩毒录影带的拷贝
I've a copy too.
我也有一个拷贝
His crime is not linked with me
他犯了罪根本跟我没关系
I can testify against you
我可以指控你
Testify against me?
指控我？
That tape
那一盒录影带
even if released to the world won't serve any purpose
在全世界发行都没有问题
Because only Te can testify against me
因为指控我的人祗有德叔一个
Vincent, yes, I'm Michael
云逊，是，我是米高
Finish off Te right away
马上替我把德叔干掉
I'll hand the stuff over to you in person
货我会亲自交给你
We've been getting on well
我们一直相处得很开心
because you're obedient
因为你听我的指使
But, unfortunately...
不过，很可惜…
Mr Feng, telephone
请叫冯先生听电话
Yes, speaking
是，我是
The long distance call to Canada is connect
加拿大长途电话接通了
Thank you
谢谢
Darling
孩子
Daddy
爸爸
Yes
是呀
What is it?
什么事
I'll fly to Canada
我明天大清早七点
at 7 tomorrow morning
就坐飞机到加拿大去
What?
什么
The Hq has approved my early retirement
警察部说我身体不好
for health reasons
批准我提早退休
Have you received my remittance?
我寄给你的钱收到了没有？
Don't move
不许动
Old Te...
老鬼德…
No monkey business!
另叮乱来
Hell with you!
你去死吧！
Damn, I'll kill you...
你妈的！我打死你这个家伙…
Kill...
打…
Let's go
走啦！
Have you found out everything?
你查清楚了吗？
This resignation letter has explained everything
这一封辞职信里面
I'm extremely sorry
对于我这一次这么晚才发现…
My subordinate's misbehavior till now
我觉得很抱歉
I ready for disciplinary action & investify
我愿意接受纪律处分
But I've a request
不过我有个要求
I wish I could arrest these men myself
我希望亲手抓住这一班人
I hope Mr Wei will give me this chance
在我离职之前
before I leave
希望韦长官多给我一个机会
Good, go ahead
好！你去做吧
Thank you, sir
谢谢长官
Ladies and gentleman
各位，我们有足够证据…
we've ample evidence against
证明何雪玲督察，冯建德警长
Insp Ho. Serg Feng
方信有探员，涉嫌贩毒
and detective Fang for drug-trafficking
令大家蒙上污点
I personally can't shirk the responsible for this disgrace
我实在难辞其咎
They're now fugitives with arms
现在他们畏罪潜逃，并且藏有枪械
We must bring them to book
我们一定要将他们缉捕归案
Please put personal feelings aside
希望各位暂时放下私人的感情
Shoot anyone on sight who tries to resist
如果逮捕的时候遇到反抗
Bitch
死三八
I've already done what you want.
你要我做的事我已经做了
What about the stuff?
你还没有把货给我
Let me finish off that bitch
先让我把那个三八干掉
No. I'll fix her for you
不可以，这个三八由我替你搅定
I'll take your life if I can't get the cargo tonight
今天晚上如果我拿不到货
3388, yes
3388，是！
Fang & Te have got Michael's drug
告诉他方信有和德叔
trafficking proof in Jackson Road
在积臣道找到了米高黄贩毒资料
Tell her to come at once
叫她尽快来
Yes, thank you
是，谢谢
All the cargo is in the car
所有货全在车子后面
Making fun of me? Damn you
你耍我，妈的
Michael Huang
米高黄
Damn killing you with I shot is too good for you
你妈的，一枪打死你便宜了你
I want you to be a limply in jail all your life
我要你变成瘸子，坐一辈子牢
You're wanted. What have you got to arrest
你是通辑犯，你凭什么拉我
My will power
凭我
Even by going to jail I must testify against you double dealer
我宁愿坐牢
Come out!
出来！
Come out double-crosser
出来，奸狗
Be flexible my gun's still with you
随机应变，我的枪还在你那里
Get out!
滚出来
Damn you double-crosser I'll kill you
去你妈的…死奸狗…打死你
I made much money for you
我帮你赚了这么多钱
and you got men to kill me?
你找人来想干掉我
I'll kill you double crosser
我打死你这个奸狗
I must take your life
要你的命
None can testify against me when you're dead
你死了就没有人可以指证我
Let's perish together
哪就同归于尽好了
Scum, traitor, I'll kill you
孬种，奸狗，我撞死你
I'm Anti Hareotics Insp Huang.
我是扫毒组总督察米高黄
He's wanted arrest him
他是被通缉的毒犯，拘捕他
You're a drug trafficker
你才是毒犯
You lie
你说谎
Don't move let's talk it over in the headquarter
不许动，有什么事回警察局再说
Michael
米高
We now have ample evidence for your drug
不用说了，现在有充分的证据…
trafficking you're under arrest
证明你贩毒，我要拘捕你
Keep away, or I'll kill her
别过来，不然我打死她
Run
走呀
Michael, you're no chance. Give up
米高，你没有机会走了，投降吧
With her in my hands
我手上有她，还有机会
I do & I won't give up
我不会放过任何机会
So we meet again
想不到我们又在一起了
Drive the car over
把车子开过来
Drive the car over away
把车子开过去
Yes sir
是，长官
Hold it
先不要走
Thank you.
委屈你们了
Without your help I would have cracked this case
没有你两位我破不了这一宗案子
I'll make good the grievances you've suffered
至于你们所受的委屈